Guide to the Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004.
Renew Media/Rockefeller Foundation Fellowships in New Media Art 2003-2004
- Series IV. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2006
  - Project Proposal: The Distance Between What we Want and what we Have: Arctic Project 2006(includes 3 pp. maps and color diagrams of proposed installation), Strachan, Tavares (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Slides:
      - 10 Slides(Documentation of artworks Natural body water (2002), I can’t forget what I have forgotten (2003), Two things existing simultaneously (2003), The Sound of an ant Walking (2003), Double Rack (2002), Light Blue Clatter (2005), and Light from the Bahamas (2003))
    - DVD:
      - Double Rack (2003)(documentation of installation)
      - The Sound of an ant Walking (2002)(documentation of installation)
    - Print Materials:
      - images of newspaper articles about the artist (3 pages)
      - images of completed phases of The Arctic Ice Project (4 pages)
  - Project Proposal: Survivors: Uploaded and Resurrected, Tolchinsky, Debra, and Dave Tolchinsky (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - DVD:
      - Sample Work(documentation of artist's installations Going UP?, Cleave, and Lucky-Dolly-Max)
    - Print:
      - Press cards from SiteUnseen and Going UP?(3 copies)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Debra Tolchinsky Artist Website
  - Project Proposal: The EcoRaft Project, Tomlinson, Bill (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Sample Work(2-3 minute Quicktime videos of installations Alphawolf (2001), The Virtual Raft Project (2004), and an 8-minute Quicktime movie of the animated film Shaft of Light(1996))
      - Supplementary Work(documentation of proposed artwork EcoRaft)
  - Project Proposal: Hyperfilm 1.0, Vega, John (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Filmtext (2002)
      - Wirescapes 1.0 (2003)
      - Hyperstills (2004)
      - Automatic Handwriting (2005)
      - Wirescapes 2.0 (prototype) (2004)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Filmtext (2002)
      - Wirescapes 1.0 (2003)
      - Hyperstills (2004)
      - Automatic Handwriting (2005)
      - Wirescapes 2.0 (prototype) (2004)
  - Project Proposal: Speaking Statues(includes detailed diagram of proposed installation), Wodiczko, Krzysztof (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - VHS:
      - Tijuana (2001)(documentation of live performance and interview project)
    - Print materials:
      - color images of related public art projects (5 pages)
  - Project Proposal: Trigger, Zellen, Jody (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Work Samples(includes documentation of artworks Ghost City (1997-2005), Disembodied Voices (2003-2004) and Trigger/Random Acts from Everyday Life (2005))
    - Print Materials:
      - 4 artist books: City Views (2001), Standing Still: Still Standing (1999-2000), The Blackest Spot (2002), Other Places (2004)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Ghost City, Trigger
      - Disembodied Voices
      - Artist Website
- Series V. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2007
  - Project Proposal: Dress the Dress(includes color diagrams and sketches of proposed installation; 2 copies), Akiyoshi, Megumi (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - DVD:
      - ON/megumi Akiyoshi Sample Work(includes video documentation of artworks Coffin for the Living (2004, 2002); mini Coffin for the Living (2003); Cyberwomb (2000-2004); ON Museum Times Square (2006))
    - CD-ROM:
      - ON/megumi Akiyoshi Sample Work(includes 13 jpg images of artworks Coffin for the Living (2004, 2002); mini Coffin for the Living (2003); Cyberwomb (2000-2004); ON Museum Times Square (2006))
      - ON/megumi Akiyoshi Supplemental(includes scans of exhibition reviews in Spanish, Chinese, and English)
  - Project Proposal: Inventor’s Paradise, Allen, Mark (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - CD-Rom:
      - Machine Project(PowerPoint presentation of performance/installation)
    - Print:
      - How to Make your Own Hyperbolic Book(paper cutout project, 6 pages)
      - Happenings Cal Arts newsletter, Spring 2006(article on Machine Project by Margaret Crane)
      - Letter from artist regarding book about projects
      - Color photocopies from book, At the Edge of Art, including descriptions and images of C-Level and Machine Project events
      - Review of Machine Project by Valerie Palmer
      - The Believer September 2006(includes interview with the artist by Joshuah Bearman)
      - X-Tra: Contemporary Art Quarterly 9:1(includes interview with the artist by Ken D. Allan)
  - Project Proposal: Anamorphosis(includes descriptions of works The Morphology of Desire (ver. 3), and Zeno’s Paradox, and images of anamorphic projection schemes), Arnold, Robert F. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - VHS:
      - The Morphology of Desire (ver. 3), 2006 continuous play loop, 7:30 Zeno’s Paradox, 2004 continuous play loop, 7:15
    - DVD:
      - The Morphology of Desire (ver. 3) 2006 continuous play, random sequencing
      - Zeno’s Paradox 2004 continuous play, random sequencing
  - Project Proposal: Computational Sculpture(includes descriptions of works i:move series (2003-4), Protochoice (2005), Social Fabric (2006), Swarm Robots (2003-4), Topobo substrate (2003-6), backup series (2004-6), fotron2000 (2004-5), intimacy machine (2005), Impalpable (2005)), Bachrach, Jonathan (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - DVD:
      - Samples(includes still images, text description, and video demonstrations of works i:move, Protochoice, and Social Fabric)
      - Supplementals(includes still images, text description, and video demonstrations of works Swarm Robots, Topobo Body, backUP, Intimacy Machine, fotron2000, scribbler)
  - Project Proposal: Amy and Klara’s Friends(includes descriptions and b/w images of installations The Universal Whistling Machines Project (2004-5) and Amy and Klara (2006)), Böhlen, Marc (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://www.realtechsupport.org/new_works/friends.html
      - The Universal Whistling Machines Project (U.W.M.)
      - Amy and Klara
    - Print:
      - Color photocopies of images from installations Amy and Klara and The Universal Whistling Machines Project
  - Project Proposal: SprawlCode: Descriptions in a Constructed Language, Burnett, Christopher (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - CD-ROM:
      - SprawlCode-book.pdf((pdf version of artist’s book to be published in 2006))
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://vws.org/cb/work/
        (online version of artist’s statement and portfolio, including information about projects Information Machine (1987-89), LogoFuturism (1989), Agents of Time (1991), Muto(scape) (1993), Against Nature 2 (1995), Tomorrowland (1996), Las Vegas: Capital of the 21st Century (1996), Western Skies (1997), Road to Sun Interface (2001), Messages to Extinct Places (2004), Extinct Animals (2004))
      - online version of artist’s book
      - online version of print brochures
    - Print:
      - Brochure, Sculptural User Interface / Artificial Sculpture, 2 copies
  - Project Proposal: Open/Stories(Closed/Stores), Christensen, Julia (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - DVD-ROM:
      - Big Box Reuse Web Site Files(local copy of project website)
    - Print materials:
      - Color photocopies of articles about the artist’s Big Box Reuse project, including an article by the artist, Orion, Jan/Feb 2006, “Redemption Center”; Rensselaer, Summer 2005, “Recycling the Big Box,”
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Big Box Reuse Project
  - Project Proposal:, Collins, Nicholas (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Print materials:
      - Criticism of installation Daguerrotypes Score and notes related to audio installation Truth in Clouds Essay by the artist on Devil’s Music (English text and published German version, photocopied from Material Re Material—remix and copyright, MaerzMusik: Festival für aktuelle Musik, Berliner Festspiele, 2003)
    - VHS:
      - Daguerrotypes
      - Truth in Clouds
    - DVD:
      - Daguerrotypes
      - Truth in Clouds
    - Audio CD:
      - Devil’s Music
    - CD-ROM:
      - Devil’s Music software (Mac OSX)
  - Project Proposal: Youth of the Apocalypse(includes color images and screen shots of previous installations), Condon, Brody (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - DVD:
      - Brody Condon
  - Project Proposal: Havidol (r), Cooper, Justine (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Transformers(2 Quicktime videos documenting installation, 2002-2003)
    - DVD:
      - TULP: the body public(performance with John Rodgers, composer, and the Elison Ensemble), 2004. Includes full documentation video of performance at Brisbane Festivals (65 min.) and preview video (4:30).)
    - DVD-ROM:
      - Havidol(Quicktime demos of videos for proposed project)
  - Project Proposal: Creative Citizen Science(PiegonBlog2.0 and Urban Blue), da Costa, Beatriz (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - CD-ROM:
      - DaCosta Rockefell 2006(includes documentation of projects PigeonBlog (2006); Swipe (2002-2004); GenTerra (2001-2003))
  - Project Proposal: Tracking Transience: The Orwell Project, Elahi, Hasan (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Tracking Transience: The Orwell Project
  - Project Proposal: Memoria/Memoir(includes diagram and floor plan of proposed installation), Flax, Carol (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - VHS:
      - Carol Flax Work Samples(includes documentation of installations Ex/Changing Families (1997/98), Journeys 1900/2000 (2000), memoria/memoir (2006))
    - CD-ROM:
      - Carol Flax Supplemental Materials(includes documentation of interactive installations Ex/Changing Families and Journeys: 1900/2000, web art works 2 mothers and Tuesday Afternoon, DVD installations kyle and 2 mothers, and images of print materials. Windows and Firefox browser recommended.)
    - Print materials:
      - foldout pamphlet/program with critical essay by Shelley Lawrence about installation memoria/memoir (2006)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - memoira/memoir
      - Journeys 1900/2000
  - Project Proposal: “Desire”, Gaiter, Colette (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Colette Gaiter Samples 1, 2, 3 of 4(includes versions of projects WHICH Hue are You? (2005), Space/Race (1995-1998)
      - Colette Gaiter Sample 4 of 4
  - Project Proposal: Peek-a-boo’s Cave(includes diagram of proposed installation), Gast, Christy (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - VHS:
      - Christy Gast Work Sample Video (includes documentation of installation Female Soldier Ballads / Amazonian News Network (2005), Left Mitten (The Great Denudation) (2004), Free Radio High Desert Test Sites (2004))
      - Christy Gast Supplemental Sample Work Video(compilation of footage from two sites relevant to the proposed installation)
    - Audio CD:
      - Female Soldier Ballads (includes the songs “Flack Jacket and Camo Trousers or The Ballad of Lori Piestewa,” “Lynndie England or The Misadventures of a Female MP at Abu Ghraib Prison,” and “The Female Volunteers or A Tale of Two POWs”)
  - Project Proposal:, Haddock, Jon (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Isometric Screenshots (2001)
      - Internet Sex Photos (Pornography with the People Removed) (1999)
      - Modifications (2001)
  - Project Proposal: Bio-Metric Soul Catcher, Hershman, Lynn (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - VHS:
      - Synthia Ticker(documentation of 2002 installation)
      - DiNA(documentation of 2006 installation)
    - DVD:
      - The Art and Films of Lynn Hershman Leeson: Secret Agents, Private I (2005)
      - (Her)rata ! Women + Art = Revolution
    - Book and DVD
      - The Art and Films of Lynn Hershman Leeson: Secret Agents, Private I. Edited by Meredith Tromble. Berkeley, Los Angeles, and London: University of California Press, 2005. (Includes second copy of DVD The Art and Films of Lynn Hershman Leeson)
    - Print materials:
      - “The Raw Data Diet, All-Consuming Bodies and the Shape of Things to Come,” illustrated essay by the artist, published in Leonardo Vol. 38, no. 3, 2005, p. 208-212.
      - Color copy of review by Mark Bell of Hershman’s 2006 film Strange Culture, from Film Threat website
      - Color copy of review by Kirk Honeycutt of Strange Culture, from Hollywood Reporter website.
      - “Almost Famous: New Media Pioneer Lynn Hershman Leeson Gets her Due,” essay by Elizabeth Bard, published in Contemporary. Issue information unknown. Includes images of selected installations by the artist.
      - Color copy of excerpt from “Pardon Me, but the Art is Mouthing Off,” article published in the NY Times Sunday, November 7, 2005. Illustrated.
      - Proposal and dossier for (Her)rata: Art, Women, and Revolution
  - Project Proposal: Trans-Tamagotchi: Virtual Trans Research, High, Kathy (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - VHS:
      - Animal Attraction (59”, 2000)
      - Playing with Rats(documentation of rats in installation Embracing Animal)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Slides for Embracing Animal installation
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Embracing Animal
  - Project Proposal: Gas Busters(includes b/w screenshots from digital works “Jesus is da Bomb” (2003), “When Ronald MaoDonald married MaoDonna” (2002), “Saint Bush and Saint Cheney from Holyburton brings you the supersized melting-pot Jesus,” (2003), “MeccaDonald’s Happy Meal! I’m Lovin’ it!” (2003), BradfordRivers,net (2004-5), and Global Presidential Election (2006)), Hung, Kenneth Tin-Kin (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - 60x1.com
        (2001-2007)
      - www.BradfordRivers.net
        (2004-5)
      - Global Presidential Election
        (2003-2007)
  - Project Proposal: Sensorial Triggers, Katrencik, Emily (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - DVD:
      - Selected Works(includes excerpts of performances Consuming 1.956 Inches (3) Each Day for Forty-One Days (2005); Consuming Architecture (2000); Finding the Socialism Within the Capitalism (2000-2003))
      - Consuming 1.956 Inches (3) Each Day for Forty-One Days (2005)
  - Project Proposal: Deep Wounds South, Knep, Brian (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - DVD:
      - Brian Knep(includes documentation of installations Healing #1 (3:51, 2003-4), Drip, Drip Ticker, and Drip Escalator (1:10, 2004-5), and Deep Wounds (4:19, 2006)
    - Print material: (color photocopies of illustrated articles)
      - Shawn Hill, “Brian Knep’s Deep Wounds at Memorial Hall, Harvard University,” Art New England Aug/Sept 2006, p. 9.
      - Pien Huang, “Installation explores price of conflict: Knep’s ‘Deep Wounds’ at Memorial Hall,” Harvard University Gazette, 2006.
      - Geoff Edgers, “Is there an artist in the house?” The Boston Globe, Friday, April 7, 2006, D5, D18\
  - Project Proposal: Inflatable Bodies / Inflatable Architectural Body(includes sketches and diagrams of proposed installation), MacMurtrie, (Francisco) Chico (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - VHS:
      - Chico MacMurtrie: Sample Work(includes clips from works Inflatable Bodies; Growing, Raining Tree (2003); Forest of Telescoping Totem Poles (2005); 16 Birds (2006); Totemobile (2006))
    - Print Materials:
      - b/w photocopies of illustrated catalog of works by Amorphic Robot Works studio
      - Selected print reviews of the artist’s exhibitions, in English, Spanish, and Portuguese
  - Project Proposal: Cybotanomy: Cybernetics, Botany, and Autonomous Robotics. The life cycle of plants in post-human environments(includes b/w and color visualizations and diagrams of the proposed project), Marchal, Noah (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - The Pilot Project
      - The Catcher Network
      - Satellite
    - CD-ROM:
      - Noah Marchal Sample Works(off-line version of artist’s website. Includes documentation, diagrams, and descriptions of projects The Pilot Project, The Catcher Network, and Satellite.)
  - Project Proposal: Knitoscope Sampler, Mazza, Cat (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - DVD:
      - Knitoscope Sampler(includes videos Knitoscope Sampler, microRevolt, and Film to Fiber)
    - Print Materials:
      - b/w photocopies with illustrations of various reviews, articles, interviews, and other press coverage of the artists’ projects microRevolt
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - microRevolt.org (2004-2007)
  - Project Proposal: Invisible Rooms(includes color diagram of proposed installation), Meza, Abinadi (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - DVD:
      - Abinadi Meza 3 Work Samples(includes documentation of installations Majestic, Quiet, and Empty like a Monster (2003), Soft Jaws (2004), and Silence (2005))
    - CD-ROM:
      - Abinadi Meza Website on CD-ROM
  - Project Proposal: Informationalism: Ideology(includes b/w diagram of proposed installation and color images of projects Public Broadcast Cart, From Darkness to Daylight, and Vagamundo: A Migrant’s Tale), Zuniga, Ricardo Miranda (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - DVD:
      - Ricardo Miranda Zúñiga(includes documentation of works Public Broadcast Cart (2003-6), From Darkness to Daylight (2004), Vagamundo: A Migrant’s Tale (2002))
    - Website:(online versions of work samples on DVD)
      - Public Broadcast Cart
      - From Darkness to Daylight
      - Vagamundo: A Migrant’s Tale
  - Project Proposal: Moving Camera Studies, Naimark, Michael (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - DVD:
      - Naimark Rockefeller 2007 Sample(includes samples of “moviemap” projects (1978-1994) and installations Displacements (1980-4/2005) and Be Now Here (1995-97))
  - Project Proposal: Vortex(includes 2 color visualizations of installation), Osborn, Ed (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - DVD:
      - Harvester(documentation of 2004 sound installation Harvester)
      - Media Arts Fellowship Application(2 copies; includes documentation of installations Harvester (2004); Particle Moves (2003); Flying Machines (2001); Night-Sea Music (1998); Flyover (2002))
    - Print Material:
      - Work and Exhibition Information for Selected Projects(includes descriptions, exhibition histories, and color images of several installations, 1996-2006)
  - Project Proposal: Institute for Transgeneography(includes b/w visualization of transgenetic organism development), Pell, Richard (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - DVD:
      - “Bridging the Gap” Institute for Applied Autonomy(title on disc: Rich Pell 2007 Fellow) (Brief documentary video about the artist’s previous projects, including Contestational Robotics, iSee, TXTmob)
  - Project Proposal: The Inevitable(includes b/w photocopy of visualization of proposed installation), Ralske, Kurt (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - DVD:
      - ¨Kurt Ralske 2007 Fellow(includes documentation of works Times Square Timeshare (2006), MoMA Display Screens (2004), and Darkness (Not Darkness) (2005))
  - Project Proposal: Catalogue(to the Universe and its Stars) (includes b/w and color diagrams and images for the proposed installation), Salavon, Jason (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - DVD:
      - Sample Work(off-line version of the artist’s website)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - http://salavon.com/nvr
        (includes description and documentation of works Still Life at the Speed of Sunrise (2005), Everything, All at Once (2005), The Late Night Triad (2003))
  - Project Proposal: Change of State, Scher, Julia (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - DVD:
      - Excerpts (1989-2000)(title on disc: Julia Scher Works Samples)(includes excerpts from video installations Security by Julia XXXXIII, Security by Julia IV, Institutional State, Vigilance)
    - CD-ROM:
      - “Stills”(includes photographic documentation of three installations, Security by Julia XLV (2002), Wonderland (1998), and Glückshabe (2006))
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Change of State
      - www.kunstsommer.cccmz.de
      - www.walkerart.org
      - http://www.walkerart.org/collections.walkerart.org/itemobject/html
      - http://www.walkerart.org/project/secure/corridor/sec1.html
      - http://www.insecuritybyjulia.thing.net
  - Project Proposal: The Well(includes color stills and screenshots from works on sample discs), Shor, Shirley (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - DVD:
      - DVD #1(includes description and documentation of artworks Landslide(2004), Lining (2005), Sculptural Information (2005), Rhizome (2003), The Book of Life (2004), and Becoming an Artist and Becoming Me (2004))
      - DVD #2(includes documentation, without titles, of artworks Split (2003), Elevation (2005), See Saw/Core/Primitive Notions (2005))
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Terra Infirma, 2005
    - Print materials:
      - Catalogue to accompany Shirley Shor: On the Fly, exhibition at Moti Hasson Gallery, 2006. Includes color illustrations and critical essay, “Dynamic Territories and Shifting Landscapes,” by Irene Hofman.
      - Catalogue to accompany Measure of Time, exhibition at the University of California, Berkeley Art Museum and Pacific Film Archive, 2006-7. Includes essay by Lucinda Barnes, curator, with description and color illustrations of artwork Landslide.
  - Project Proposal: Famous Flowers, Steinkamp, Jennifer (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - DVD:
      - Steinkamp DVD(includes documentation of works Dervish (2004-5), The River of No Return (2004), Jimmy Carter (2002), Eye Catching (2003))
  - Project Proposal: Dark Dream: A Journey into Cambodia’s Past and Back Again(includes installation diagrams and color photographs for proposed project and sample works on DVD), Sutton, Eva (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - DVD:
      - Sample Projects(includes demo videos of installations Monument to the Year Zero (2004-5), Mutations (2002-3), Chance Transmission: An I Ching Reading With Two Small Robots (2005))
    - Print Materials:
      - Catalogue, Almost Human: Dolls and Robots in Contemporary Art, from exhibition at Hunterdon Museum of Art, 2005.(Includes description and color photographs of installation Chance Transmission)
      - Catalogue, Genomic Issue(s): Art and Science, from exhibition at Art Gallery of the Graduate Center of the City University of New York, 2003.(Includes description and b/w photograph of installation Mutations)
      - Camerawork: A Journal of Photographic Arts, 31 n. 2, Fall/Winter 2004.(Includes description and b/w photographs of installation Monument to the Year Zero)
  - Project Proposal: Somnolescent Intelligence, Bill Tomlinson (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - CD-ROM:
      - Bill Tomlinson(includes video documentation of installations EcoRaft Project (2005) and Alpha Wolf (2001), and the short film Shaft of Light (1996))
  - Project Proposal: Temporal Contraptions, Utterback, Camille (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - VHS:
      - Camille Utterback(includes works Potent Objects (2003), 2.06; External Measures (2003), 1.33; Untitled 5 (2004), 3.09)
    - Print materials:
      - Camille Utterback: Engaging Space(guide to exhibit at Mass MoCA, 2002)
      - Four Americans(catalogue to exhibition at Marlborough Gallery, 2004)
  - Project Proposal: ShiftSpace, Zer-Aviv, Mushon (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - CD-ROM:
      - ShiftSpace: The Social Layer Above the Web(includes demos and description illustrations of proposed artwork Shift Space, as well as documentation of projects Permanent Borders (2005); Graffiti Studio: Separation Wall (2005); You Are Not Here (2006), Where’s Ascii? (2002-2005); Upgrade! (2005-2008)) (Windows preferred)
    - Website: (May no longer function)
      - Graffiti Studio: Separation Wall
- Series VI. Rockefeller New Media Fellowships 2008
  - Project Proposal: Scalable Cities, Brown, Sheldon (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - DVD-ROM:
      - Sheldon Brown Slides (includes installation views and screen grabs of proposed artwork Scalable Cities and short videos of Scalable Cities, Excerpts, and Smoke and Mirrors)
    - DVD:
      - Sheldon Brown: Works (includes brief artist bio, documentation of artworks Smoke and Mirrors, Istoria, Mi Casa es Tu Casa, Video Wind Chimes, Apparitions, In The Event, and Metastasis, and a general overview video of work excerpts)
    - Website: (May no longer function)